# Ryan Andersen

+1 (801) 898-9648 github

Junior Software Developer experienced in website and application design, with a strong understanding of art and design fundementals, and a knack for solving unique problems with creative solutions. Interested in working alone or in a team to develop aesthetically pleasing and highly functional projects.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Ryan Andersen Co (Software, Design)

(Remote) St George, UT

Dec 2022 - Present

#### Software Developer

- Designed and developed websites and applications for clients.
- Created and maintained websites for personal projects.

**Utah Tech University Sears Art Museum** (art, history, education, social media)

St George, UT

#### Art Director Intern

Jan 2022 - Sep 2023

- Responsible for handling and cataloging various works of art.
- Assisted with setting up and hanging prestigious art shows and assisting featured artists.
- Collaborated on the posting of company social media and website content.

Caption Call (Communication, Technology)

St George, UT

**Captioning Agent** 

Jun 2020 - Dec 2021

- · Transcribed personal conversations from speech to text for hearing disabled persons, requiring the highest possible accuracy of transcription.
- Communicated effectively and professionally with mentors and team members through team chat and live calls.
- Maintained highest quality performance throughout numerous unannounced quality checks.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Utah Tech University**

Aug 2019 - Dec 2022

Bachelor of Science

Graduated Magna Cum Laude

Applied Technology Certificate in 3D Animation

## Salt Lake Community College

Aug 2013 - Dec 2018

Associate of Science

- Certificate of Proficiency in Audio Production

## **SKILLS**

The leftmost label in a row signifies some area of expertise, followed by links to public projects that showcase it. On the right end of each row are some dots and bubbles that represent my comfort level in the domain—the more bubbles, the more familiar it is.

